A Finding Aid to the John Steuart Curry and Curry Family Papers, 1848-1999, bulk 1916-1946, in the Archives of American Art AAA.currjohn
Archives of American Art
- Photographs, circa 1900-1998; Series 8; (Boxes 5-6, OV 14; 1.1 linear feet)
  - Photographs of Works of Art (Box 6)
    - Murals (Box 6)
      - Department of Justice Building (1936-1937), undated; (not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 35)
      - Kansas Murals (1938-1940), undated; (3 folders; not scanned; see also OV 14) (Box 6, Folder 36-38)
      - Kansas Murals, Models and Source Material (1938-1940), undated (Box 6, Folder 39)
      - University of Wisconsin Biochemistry Building (1940-1942), undated; (not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 40)
      - University of Wisconsin Law Library (1940-1942), undated; (not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 41)
        (for a sketch of the site of this mural, see Artwork)
      - Unidentified Murals, undated; (not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 42)
        (possibly First National Bank murals in Madison, Wisconsin)
    - Negatives, undated; (4 folders; not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 43-46)
    - Restoration Before and After Photographs, 1994, 1996, undated (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - Photostats, undated; (not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - Works of Art by Other Artists, undated; (not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Oversized Photographs (from Box 5, folders 39 and 42; and Box 6, folders 17 and 38) (Box OV 14)
- Artwork, 1941, undated; Series 9; (Box 7, OV 12, 14, 15; 0.2 linear feet)
  This series includes sketches, a cartoon of Curry, and test canvases. Four sketches are found by John Steuart Curry, including one small watercolor sketch of corn, and a sketch of what appears to be the site of his mural in the Wisconsin Law Library.
  Seven test canvases, two of them dated 1941, are annotated with notes regarding the materials used for the various colors and grounds represented.
  Additional sketches are found in Subject Files, and in Curry's childhood scrapbook in Print Materials. Scattered illustrated letters from Curry can also be found in Family Correspondence.
  - Sketches by Curry, undated; (See also OV 14) (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Cartoon Depicting Curry, undated; (See OV 14) (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Test Canvases, undated; (See also OV 12 and 15) (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Oversized Test Canvases (from Box 7, folder 3) (Box OV 12)
  - Oversized Sketches and Cartoon (from Box 7, folders 1 and 2) (Box OV 14)
  - Oversized Test Canvas (from Box 7, folder 3) (Box OV 15)
- Estate Papers, circa 1946-1999; Series 10; (Boxes 7-9 and rolled document; 2.3 linear feet)
  This series contains papers created and gathered by Kathleen Curry and other family members after John Steuart Curry's death 1946. Types of materials include writings, published articles, correspondence, inventories of artwork and papers, and various business records kept by Kathleen Curry. Also found are alphabetical files dating roughly 1983 to 1999, which contain correspondence, clippings, catalogs, receipts, photographs, and other records related to museums, galleries, and other parties who dealt with the estate.
  Articles about Curry include writings by family, friends, and scholars, both published and unpublished. Among the family writings are several articles written by Curry siblings, and notes written by R. Eugene Curry which refer to the papers themselves, especially to letters in Family Correspondence. Other articles include journal publications and writings related to exhibitions. Journal articles are accompanied by critical responses written to their authors from Kathleen Curry.
  Chronological files of correspondence contain letters primarily from 1946 through 1980, although some later correspondence is found here. Alphabetical files contain most of the correspondence and other documents of the estate from about 1983 to 1999. Both the chronological correspondence and alphabetical files document publications, exhibitions, appearances, sales, disposition of papers, Curry-related events, and financial matters, with scattered personal correspondence. The estate's relationships with galleries representing Curry's artwork are heavily documented in this series. These include Associated American Artists, Robert Graham Galleries, and Kennedy Galleries in the chronological correspondence, and Mongerson Wunderlich, and Vivian Kiechel Fine Art in the alphabetical files. Correspondence between Kathleen Curry and many of her husband's colleagues is found, primarily in the chronological correspondence, including Thomas Hart Benton (1946), Thomas Craven, George Macy, Laurence Schmeckebier, Bob Hodgell, Don Anderson, Lloyd Garrison, Burton Cumming, William McCloy, and Maynard Walker. Letters between Laurence Schmeckebier and various family members (1981-1984), written for research on a revised edition of his biography of Curry (not published) includes letters with reminiscences of Curry's early life. A placard created to commemorate Curry's mural in the Law Library of the University of Wisconsin is found with a letter from Lloyd Garrison of 1948.
  Inventories include lists of artwork, slides, papers, and reproductions. Most of the signed inventories were created by either Kathleen Curry or galleries representing Curry's artwork. Many are unsigned and unidentified.
  Additional papers dated after Curry's death can be found in Print Materials, Personal Business Records, and Photographs. Additional information about Curry's family can be found in Biographical Materials and Family Correspondence.
  - Articles about Curry, circa 1946-1993; (3 folders) (Box 7, Folder 4-6)
    (includes manuscript and published articles by Stephen C. Behrendt, Patricia S. Leddy, William McCloy, and John F. Helm, Jr., as well as Kathleen Curry's responses to articles)
  - Articles about Curry, Writings by Family Members, circa 1940, 1972-1988; (3 folders) (Box 7, Folder 7-9)
    (includes articles by Margaret Curry Fike, Margery Curry Yeakley, Ellen Curry Schuster, and notes and essays by R. Eugene Curry)
  - Articles about Curry, Photocopies of Articles Gathered by Family Members (1936-1981), undated; (not scanned) (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Copyright Permissions, circa 1959-1997; (3 folders) (Box 7, Folder 11-13)
  - Correspondence (Box 7)
    - Condolence Letters, 1946; (7 folders) (Box 7, Folder 14-20)
    - General Correspondence, 1946-1950; (7 folders; see also rolled document) (Box 7, Folder 21-27)
    - General Correspondence, circa 1951-1959; (14 folders) (Box 7, Folder 28-41)
    - General Correspondence, 1960-1969; (10 folders) (Box 7, Folder 42-51)
    - General Correspondence, 1970-1979; (6 folders) (Box 8, Folder 1-6)
    - General Correspondence, circa 1981-1998 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Undated Correspondence, Kathleen Curry, circa 1946-1998 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Undated Correspondence, Miscellaneous Authors, circa 1946-1977 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Greeting Cards, circa 1946-1985 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Legal Correspondence, 1946, circa 1976-1989 (Box 8, Folder 11)
      (Lloyd Garrision, Kathleen Curry, John Silberman)
  - Inventories (Box 8)
    - Artwork in the Home of Kathleen Curry, West Newbury, CT, circa 1946-1952 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Artwork Owned by Family Members, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Kennedy Galleries, circa 1975-1984 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Mongerson Wunderlich, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous Inventories and Lists, circa 1947-1988 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - John Steuart Curry Papers in the Posession of Kathleen Curry, circa 1971 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Slide Collection and Photographs of Artwork, undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Index to Reproductions of Artwork, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, circa 1952-1992; (Not scanned) (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Personal Finances, Kathleen Curry, circa 1948-1974; (Not scanned) (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Royalty Statements, 1951-1974; (not scanned) (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Shipping Receipts and Loan Agreements, 1949-1973, 1991; (not scanned) (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Alphabetical Files (not scanned) (Box 8)
    - 100th Birthday Celebration (Kansas), 1997 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Archives of american Art and Other Smithsonian Offices, circa 1966-1998; (4 folders) (Box 8, Folder 25-28)
    - Beach Museum, Kansas State University, circa 1996-1997 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Czestochowski, Joseph, 1981-1986 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Edwin A. Ulrich Museum of Art, Wichita State University, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Elvehjem Museum, University of Wisconsin Madison, circa 1984-1999; (3 folders) (Box 8, Folder 32-34)
    - John Steuart Curry Art Guild (Oskaloosa, Kansas), 1992-1994 (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - John Steuart Curry Boyhood Home and Memorial (Oskaloose, Kansas), circa 1987-1998 (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - Kansas Publicity, circa 1986=1997 (Box 8, Folder 37)
    - Kansas State Historical Society, 1993, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 38)
    - Lambert, Don, circa 1992-1999 (Box 8, Folder 39)
    - M.H. de Young Memorial Museum, circa 1992-1998; (4 folders) (Box 8, Folder 40-43)
      (includes material related to exhibition "John Steuart Curry: Inventing the Middle West")
    - Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1997-1999 (Box 8, Folder 44)
    - Mongerson Wunderlich, 1983-1990; (3 of 10 folders) (Box 8, Folder 45-47)
    - Mongerson Wunderlich, 1991-1998; (7 of 10 folders) (Box 9, Folder 1-7)
    - Nelson Atkins Museum of Art, 1996-1999; (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 8-9)
      (includes slides of exhibition "John Steuart Curry: Inventing the Middle West")
    - Sotheby's, 1996-1997 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Spencer Museum of Art, University of Kansas (Lawrence), 1983-1997 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Westport Arts Council Award (Connecticut), 1994 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Westport Weston Arts Council Exhibition, circa 1983-1984; (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 13-14)
    - Westport Fresco Restoration, 1996-1998 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Whitehead, Fred, University of Kansas Medical Center, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Vivian Kiechel Fine Art (Lincoln, Nebraska), 1997-1999 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Oversized Enclosure from Estate Correspondence (rolled Documentfrom Box 7, folder 25; not scanned) (Box 16)